<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
	<channel>
<title>TempestTwins Blog</title><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/index.html</link><description>TempestTwins Blog</description><dc:language>en</dc:language><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><dc:rights>Copyright 2007 Ship&#x27;s Mouse</dc:rights><dc:date>2012-07-08T14:58:45+01:00</dc:date><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/" />
<admin:errorReportsTo rdf:resource="mailto:mice@mindless.com" /><sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<sy:updateBase>2000-01-01T12:00+00:00</sy:updateBase>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 10:09:55 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rather slow here</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2012-07-08T14:58:45+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/blog.php#unique-entry-id-489</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/blog.php#unique-entry-id-489</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="mouse" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/mouse.jpg" width="41" height="41" /></div>For those of you wondering, yes I have not updated here for a while.  I am rather behind and it looks as if Vampirates central www.vampirates.co.uk is doing a very good job of keeping everyone informed.  So I have added in the three missing entries on the correct dates according to their list.  It is lovely to see Vampirates are still all around the world, Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, Croatia, Ecuador, England, Ireland, Italy, Luxembourg, Malta, Mexico, Northern Ireland, Norway, Peru, Philippines, Poland, Portugal, Romania , Saudi Arabia, Scotland, Spain, Sweden, United States and of course Wales.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>La Guerra Inmortal</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-06-28T14:54:52+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/24-june-2012#unique-entry-id-488</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/24-june-2012#unique-entry-id-488</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a>La Guerra Inmortal has been released in Spain and to those of us like me that do not speak spanish, our spanish members of the crew how have their own copies of Immortal War.</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Audiobooks</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Vampirates</category><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-07-04T14:46:50+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/01-july-2012#unique-entry-id-487</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/01-july-2012#unique-entry-id-487</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>If you like listening to your stories there is good news on the horizon.  Until the end of the school holidays (31 August 2012), Whole Story Audio Books are giving a 30% discount on all Vampirates unabridged audiobooks when the code VAMP-IRAT-EWEB-SITE is typed in the basket at there website.<br /><br />Please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/whole-story-audio-books-promotio/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk/whole-story-audio-books-promotio</a> or <a href="http://www.wholestoryaudiobooks.co.uk/catalogue/artist/author/justin_somper/1036" rel="self">www.wholestoryaudiobooks.co.uk/catalogue/artist/author/justin_somper/1036</a> for more information.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>New Website</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Vampirates</category><dc:date>2012-05-30T14:27:11+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/27-may-2012#unique-entry-id-486</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/27-may-2012#unique-entry-id-486</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a>Please check out the new website.  It looks completely new.  Also it no longer has the sound effects so my volume can stay on.</div>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Family Stories</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-07-09T12:03:50+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/blog.php#unique-entry-id-485</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/blog.php#unique-entry-id-485</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>I am always on the look out for good family stories that suit small children as well as adults.  I have found another good set to add to the list of recommendations.  But for a change this is a set of four books of short stories about two regular chapters long.<br /><br />An author called Ed Wicke (http://www.blacknbluepress.info/edhome.html) visited my daughters school.  The first time I saw him i was in the hall and he swept off this hat and bowed to the kids around me.  The kids loved it, the next time I saw him he was sitting outside school selling and signing some of his books.  We bought wicked tales four, or the purple one as my daughter calls it.  Last Friday he returned to sell and sign more, so we had to get the first three to complete the set.<br /><br />We loved wicked tales four, especially the page before the story starts on the voices, my daughter with her large brown eyes can do the kitten's look very well (she not a confident reader yet an so no voices).  When my husband read a story he could not stay in a Florida accent and so the pair of Gaiters were scouse in the end.<br /><br />So if the accents do not start the giggles going the stories and occasional picture will. I don't usually like baby stories but reading about a baby throwing toys out of a cot each one named (Ted the toy tractor) even had me in giggles.<br /><br />So if you are looking for short stories as funny as Jeremy Strong's please give Ed Wicke's Wicked Tales a go.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Recruiting Officer</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><category>Vampirates</category><dc:date>2012-03-24T17:22:45+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-march-2012#unique-entry-id-484</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-march-2012#unique-entry-id-484</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>Justin wrote on his blog &rdquo;I was thrilled when Tesco.com asked me to pen an exclusive VAMPIRATES story for them. It&rsquo;s recently gone online so have a look and I hope you enjoy it. It was a bit strange for me to return to the world of VAMPIRATES after IMMORTAL WAR, but I had a lot of fun writing it.&rdquo;<br /><br />Please check it out at <a href="http://kidsbookclub.tescomagazine.com/books-and-stories/the-recruiting-officer.html" rel="self">http://kidsbookclub.tescomagazine.com/books-and-stories/the-recruiting-officer.html</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Blog Spot</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Justin Somper</category><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-02-06T14:57:03+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/05-february-2012#unique-entry-id-483</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/05-february-2012#unique-entry-id-483</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>Jessica Bromberg (@JKBromberg) wrote on twitter: <br />What's better than a vampire and a pirate? A VAMPIRATE! Check out @JustinSomper guest blog.<br />Please see <a href="http://amusingreviews.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/vampirates-immortal-war-giveaway-and.html" rel="self">http://amusingreviews.blogspot.co.uk/2012/02/vampirates-immortal-war-giveaway-and.html</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>When we make reading into a chore ...</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-01-17T22:44:02+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/15-january-2012#unique-entry-id-481</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/15-january-2012#unique-entry-id-481</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>The author Kiersten White (@kierstenwhite) wrote :<br />&ldquo;When we make reading into a chore, young people will treat it like a chore. And I never want my books equated with the dishes in the sink.&rdquo;  &ldquo;And of course I just read this where @haleshannon says that all but much better: <a href="http://oinks.squeetus.com/2012/01/in-which-i-gamely-stick-out-my-tongue.html" rel="self">oinks.squeetus.com/2012/01/in-whi&hellip;</a>&rdquo;<br /><br />I find the subject of getting people to read interesting as I had it forced on me as a kid; and being dyslexic I am not sure what else they could do.  At least when I go into my little ones class room they are trying to match up books with readers abilities.  The problem I see is getting an interest in reading without it being a chore.<br /><br />I still find Shakespeare very hard to read, yet it is a must in schools.  I recently worked out the true story of Macbeth after reading a modern translation.  No wonder I found English literature at school so hard if I could not work out the story from the words.  I still find any book that I look up words in the first chapter a disaster.  Also any book with sentences that do not make sense straight away, which is quite easy if you naturally read words wrong and find older english hard work.<br /><br />So while teaching children to read I don&rsquo;t know how to avoid making at a chore for those having difficulties.  Later on during the major exams teachers have a list from the examining board, so another hard time not destroying books.  In-between my only hope is children get introduced to books suitable for their reading level, maturity and interest, so books are not a chore.  As a family we are trying to stop books being a chore for our little one.  My hubbie reads a chapter every available night and she gets the Beano every week (which you can follow most of the stories without reading).<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>International Look It Up In A Book Day</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2012-01-17T19:01:24+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/15-january-2012#unique-entry-id-480</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/15-january-2012#unique-entry-id-480</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>The Author Philip Ardagh (@PhilipArdagh) wrote on Twitter &ldquo;With Wikipedia off-line on Wednesday 18th, how about 'International Look It Up In A Book Day'? RT if you agree. #savelibraries&rdquo;<br /><br />I am up for it, our local library is open from 10am to 6pm on wednesdays.  How about yours?<br /><br />Please see <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/PhilipArdagh/status/159220963031007232" rel="self">https://twitter.com/#!/PhilipArdagh/status/159220963031007232</a> for the original post.<br />The reason why Wikipedia is doing a blackout please see <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-16590585" rel="self">http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/technology-16590585</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Happy Holidays from YA authors</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2011-12-22T17:44:49+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-december-2011#unique-entry-id-479</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-december-2011#unique-entry-id-479</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>The Author Kimberly Derting (@kimberlyderting) posted on behalf of several young adult authors a video of everyone singing winter wonderland to wish everyone merry Christmas.  I love the idea every author had their name and the book they wrote.<br /><br />&ldquo;Video: Happy Holidays from YA authors. (Hard to believe we decided to write instead of sing, isn&rsquo;t it???) <a href="http://kimberlyderting.tumblr.com/post/14616917315/happy-holidays-from-ya-authors-hard-to-believe" rel="self">tmblr.co/ZQEXexDdF7L3</a>&rdquo;<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Books To Recommend.</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2011-12-21T09:32:28+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-december-2011#unique-entry-id-478</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-december-2011#unique-entry-id-478</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>At this time of year everyone seems to be doing wish lists or top choices. &nbsp;My eleven year old son and I chatted in the car about what books he would recommend to another child his age.<br /><br />We agreed on two. &nbsp;As this is a Vampirates fan site we tried looking at other series of books.  They had to be the first in a series of books, as if the first book is enjoyed there is more in the series to enjoy. &nbsp;Also fast paced and acceptable for boys and girls as then it is not written with just one type of person in mind and did not get bogged down in a certain scene. &nbsp;We also ignored the ones about to be turned into a film.<br /><br /><br />H.I.V.E. (Higher Institute of Villainous Education) Series by&nbsp;Mark Walden (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="http://www.markwalden.net/">www.markwalden.net</a></u></span>)<br />There are at present seven books in this series and another due out next year.<br /><br />As the title indicates it follows a small group of friends who start a new school together. &nbsp;Although this is no ordinary school this is the&nbsp;Higher Institute of Villainous Education. &nbsp;They are meant to be learning how to be villains but they seem to be much better at being loyal and protecting what they believe is important in the school. &nbsp;Which does include practicing what they have learnt in their lessons on anyone in their way.<br /><br />My son particularly likes one character that develops as the series progresses. &nbsp;My son loves computers and so I should not be surprised with his affinity to this one character. &nbsp;But without his friends around him, he would not be able to get up to the high jinks he does.<br /><br /><br />The Demon Lexicon by&nbsp;Sarah Rees Brennan (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="https://twitter.com/sarahreesbrenna">@sarahreesbrenna</a></u></span>).<br />There are a total of three books in this series and there does not look like any more being added.<br /><br />This book starts how it means to go on, Alan and Nick defending themselves (and mother upstairs) against a magician (using a demon) breaking into their house. &nbsp;Add in a sister and brother needing help and enjoy the ride into their England.<br /><br />We both enjoy books where one of the lead characters can use a sword and defend himself against anyone attacking him, and Nick has an affinity with knives, actually any blade he can use to protect those around him.  The series of books starts in Devon and they visit several other places around England, so I also enjoyed following their progress around England in my head.<br /><br /><br />Our other favourite choices and why they did not make the top two.<br /><br /><br />Bear Grylls (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="https://twitter.com/BearGrylls">@BearGrylls</a></u></span>)<br />This is a must for any child who is a scout (As he is the World Chef Scout) or into Bear Grylls series on television. &nbsp;But I am not sure how the indoor types would enjoy a survival adventure story. &nbsp;We read the second where a plane came down in Alaska.<br /><br />As we were living somewhere where the kids were still expected to play outside at breaks up to -25C at the time, it was just reaffirming what we were learning from the locals, so particularly enjoyable reading a fast paced book where we could understand why the characters reacted the why they did.<br /><br /><br />The film How to Train Your Dragon was so vaguely based on the books by&nbsp;Cressida Cowell that I believe the books should be read whether anyone has seen the film or not. &nbsp;The only things the same seemed to be the title and the main names. &nbsp;After that the film went it's own way. &nbsp;The books are good for the younger audience as there are illustrations all the way through.<br /><br /><br />The Percy Jackson series have also been made into a film. &nbsp;But as a family we really enjoyed reading the books by&nbsp;Rick Riordan at bedtime.<br /><span style="font:13px Arial, Verdana, Helvetica, sans-serif; "><br /></span><br />Books by Anthony Horowitz (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="https://twitter.com/AnthonyHorowitz">@AnthonyHorowitz</a></u></span>)<br />There is news that another short Alex Ryder story may be coming out for world book day in march. &nbsp;Which is wonderful as the teenage spy's books have come to a natural end. &nbsp;The first book was vaguely turned into a film called stormbreaker.<br /><br />Anthony Horowitz has also written the Diamond Brothers series of books which we really enjoyed. &nbsp;Where two brothers solve crimes through their detective agency. &nbsp;They never seem to have much idea of money and the younger one does have more idea on how to solve the messes they get into.<br /><br /><br />The books being read by my son's friends at the moment are&nbsp;Skulduggery&nbsp;Pleasant and the Hunger Games. &nbsp;Skulduggery Pleasant is getting darker as the series progresses (like Harry Potter did). &nbsp;For the&nbsp;Hunger Games here is a lego trailer&nbsp;<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="http://t.co/uuRKiiKY">ow.ly/83VUK</a></u></span>&nbsp;to give you some idea of the story time for the first book.<br /><br /><br />For those girls into Twilight here are a couple of series to try, complete with the obligatory love triangle.<br /><br />Cassandra Clare (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="https://twitter.com/cassieclare">@cassieclare</a></u></span>) writes two series in parallel. &nbsp;The one I prefer at the moment is the infernal devices series starting with Clockwork Angel based in Victorian London where the Shadowhunters/Nephilim defend the world from demons and police the downworlders (warlocks, werwolves, vampires and&nbsp;faerys) and of course themselves from being seen by the mundanes.<br /><br />The Iron Fey series by Julie Kagawa (<span style="color:#0C4698;"><u><a href="https://twitter.com/Jkagawa">@Jkagawa</a></u></span>) starts with the Iron King. &nbsp;It contains the characters contained in Shakespeare's Midsummer Night's Dream and brings there escapades up to date with the advent of us now dreaming about technology.<br /><br /><br />I do hope you enjoy reading in the following year as much as we did during this one.]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Review by The Stage</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-11-24T18:43:06+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/20-november-2011#unique-entry-id-477</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/20-november-2011#unique-entry-id-477</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>I would like to congratulate the Vampirates stage show for such a wonderful a review in the Stage.<br /><br />Justin Somper wrote on Twitter &ldquo;Just caught up with this fab review of the VAMPIRATES show from the Stage -&nbsp;<span style="color:#0C4698;font-weight:bold; "><a href="http://t.co/tEMl7ipu">bit.ly/qmoUTk</a></span>. Show hits Leamington Spa this weekend!&rdquo;<br />Please see <a href="http://www.thestage.co.uk/reviews/review.php/33871/vampirates">http://www.thestage.co.uk/reviews/review.php/33871/vampirates</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>My Review</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-11-13T19:08:31+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/13-november-2011#unique-entry-id-476</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/13-november-2011#unique-entry-id-476</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>I could have picked a better weekend to come down with a streaming cold.  I had a coughing fit during the sermon this morning.  At least I did better at the three o&rsquo;clock Vampirates show.<br /><br />I am really impressed how well two actors and one actress can do with just nine main props.  I was a but worried, about the fact the end had changed, but it worked and it is understandable as they played several different parts each.  So certain combinations of characters could not be on stage at the same time.<br /><br />I really enjoyed the Vampirates stage show and so did my family.  They even agreed to dress up with me although they wanted the back row of the theatre.  There were about a dozen people sitting when we arrived all adults.  I was surprised, but the families arrived shortly after us.  South Hill Park&rsquo;s studio theatre is only small and was filled with about three dozen people.<br /><br />My kids were still singing the Vampirates Shanty while I was cooking supper although it had changed to the Last Saskatchewan Pirate by the time I had finished.  I think my family will agree with me when I say it was a very good way of spending one and a quarter hours.<br /><br />For the whole Vampirates Show Tour Schedule please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a> and for Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vampirates set sail for South Hill Park</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-11-11T22:20:08+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/06-november-2011#unique-entry-id-475</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/06-november-2011#unique-entry-id-475</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>I am going to set sail and see the Vampirates play after church parade (standing round the war memorial) on Sunday.  Here is another press article, including a piece by the actress that plays Grace.<br /><a href="http://www.readingchronicle.co.uk/theguide/goingout/articles/2011/11/11/55265-vampirates-set-sail-for-south-hill-park/" rel="self">http://www.readingchronicle.co.uk/theguide/goingout/articles/2011/11/11/55265-vampirates-set-sail-for-south-hill-park/</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>&#x2019;Vampirates&#x2019; is in Notts</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-11-08T18:45:46+00:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/06-november-2011#unique-entry-id-474</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/06-november-2011#unique-entry-id-474</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>The latest tweet from Gavin Robertson (<a href="http://twitter.com/#!/comgavrob" rel="self">@comgavrob</a>) says &ldquo;&rsquo;Vampirates&rsquo; is in Notts Nov 15 & 16, & I'll will be with author <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/JustinSomper" rel="self">@JustinSomper</a>&nbsp;to discuss onstage. Matinee sold out, but book for eve shows?&rdquo;<br /><br />For the whole Vampirates Show Tour Schedule please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a> and for Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Salisbury&#x2c; Norwich&#x2c; London...</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-10-24T22:29:40+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/23-october-2011#unique-entry-id-473</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/23-october-2011#unique-entry-id-473</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>One of the many places showing the Vampirates Stage Show soon is Welwyn Garden City.  Please see <a href="http://www.whtimes.co.uk/what-s-on/vampirates_coming_to_welwyn_garden_city_1_1106267" rel="self">http://www.whtimes.co.uk/what-s-on/vampirates_coming_to_welwyn_garden_city_1_1106267</a><br /><br />The latest tweet from Gavin Robertson (<a href="http://twitter.com/#!/comgavrob" rel="self">@comgavrob</a>) says 'Vampirates' busy this week... Greenwich, Norwich, North London...&rdquo;  For the whole Vampirates Show Tour Schedule please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a> and for Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Social Networking</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2011-10-24T21:59:23+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/23-october-2011#unique-entry-id-472</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/23-october-2011#unique-entry-id-472</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>Following the idea &ldquo;Justin Somper sets up author training company to allow authors navigate the media and social networking.&rdquo;  It is interesting to see the social networking at work for the latest book by Julie Kagawa (@Jkagawa), the fourth book in the Iron Fey series called the Iron Knight.<br /><br />For anyone interested &ldquo;There will be contests and Q&A and prizes, special guests and exciting announcements, secret reveals and more.  Including ASH'S LETTER, a note he wrote to Meghan before he left for his journey in The Iron Knight. It's never been seen before, but tonight it will be revealed.  The party starts at 10pm and goes to 12 midnight, EST. If you're unsure how to join, check out TweetChat and use the hashtag #IronKnightParty. It will take you to the party. In fact, <a href="http://tweetchat.com/room/IronKnightParty" rel="self">this</a> should take you right to the room.&ldquo;  Please see <a href="http://juliekagawa.blogspot.com/2011/10/iron-knight-night-twitter-party.html" rel="self">http://juliekagawa.blogspot.com/2011/10/iron-knight-night-twitter-party.html</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Author Profile</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Justin Somper</category><dc:date>2011-10-21T14:39:53+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/16-october-2011#unique-entry-id-471</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/16-october-2011#unique-entry-id-471</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>According to this article Justin Somper sets up author training company to allow authors navigate the media and social networking.  Good luck to everyone involved in Author Profile.<br />Please see <a href="http://www.thebookseller.com/news/somper-sets-author-training-company.html" rel="self">http://www.thebookseller.com/news/somper-sets-author-training-company.html</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vampirates Show Tour</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-10-07T11:18:42+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/02-october-2011#unique-entry-id-470</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/02-october-2011#unique-entry-id-470</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>If you are wondering what these shows are like here is a write-up in the Bucks Herald.  I will not be seeing it until November so I cannot say much about it.<br /><a href="http://www.bucksherald.co.uk/lifestyle/entertainments/theatre/climb_aboard_for_a_high_seas_adventure_1_3091175" rel="self">http://www.bucksherald.co.uk/lifestyle/entertainments/theatre/climb_aboard_for_a_high_seas_adventure_1_3091175</a><br /><br />Here is a reminder on the Vampirates Show Tour Schedule for 2011, please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a><br />For Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Talk like a pirate day.</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Pirates</category><dc:date>2011-09-19T00:00:50+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-september-2011#unique-entry-id-469</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-september-2011#unique-entry-id-469</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="../pirate/phrases/phrases.html" rel="self" title="Phrases"><img class="imageStyle" alt="jolly roger" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/jollyroger.jpg" width="40" height="39" /></a></div>Arr it be talk like a pirate day.<br />Enjoy our phrases at http://tempesttwins.co.uk/pirate/phrases/phrases.html<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>27 Sept Richmond Library</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Pirates</category><dc:date>2011-09-18T10:20:01+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-september-2011#unique-entry-id-468</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/18-september-2011#unique-entry-id-468</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/mischa-glenny.jpg" width="55" height="55" /></div>I was sent a piece on forthcoming author events at Richmond Library.  This one caught my eye as it has the pirate flag on a credit card.  I had never thought cyber-thieves were modern day pirates but I guess they are.<br />
&ldquo;An evening with Misha Glenny: Author of DarkMarket: Cyberthieves, Cybercops and You<br />Tue 27 September 6:30pm - 8.00pm, Richmond Library<br /><br />In a world where we shop, bank, work and live online, DarkMarket: Cyberthieves, Cybercops and You by Misha Glenny is an extremely necessary new book.&nbsp; Misha tells the stories of the criminals, the geeks, the police, the security experts and the victims, and brings this dark underworld alive for us. Misha Glenny is an acclaimed journalist and historian, and the author of: The Rebirth of History, The Rise and Fall of Yugoslavia, A History of the Balkans and McMafia: Seriously Organised Crime. He contributes regularly to the Guardian and the Observer, plus radio and television broadcasts. He is informally consulted on a regular basis by the British Foreign Office, the US State Department and the British Army as well as being a regular keynote speaker at conferences on organized crime, globalization, south-eastern Europe and US? Europe relations.<br />Booking essential. Tickets &pound;2 including refreshments.&rdquo;<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>This Saturday in Lincoln</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-09-15T12:18:17+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-467</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-467</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>This Saturday (17th September) has the first stop on the Stage Vampirates Show in Lincoln LPAC.  I would like to wish them luck and hope all who sail across to see it enjoy it.  The tour schedule can be found here <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a><br /><br />For Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vampirates Show Tour</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-09-12T12:28:03+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-466</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-466</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>Now that Bracknell theatre has updated it&rsquo;s &lsquo;whats on&rsquo; list and tickets are available.  Here is a reminder on the Vampirates Show Tour Schedule for 2011 web address, please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a><br /><br />For Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Audiobooks</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Vampirates</category><dc:date>2011-09-12T12:19:59+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-465</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-465</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>&rdquo;Whole Story Audiobooks &ndash; publishers of the complete Vampirates series as thrilling Unabridged Audiobooks &ndash; has joined with&nbsp;Justin to bring you an exciting offer to celebrate the release of Immortal War on the&nbsp;1st September 2011. &nbsp;The first ten copies of Immortal War bought from <a href="http://www.wholestoryaudiobooks.co.uk/catalogue/title/vampirates_immortal_war/13851" rel="self">www.wholestoryaudiobooks.co.uk</a> will include a cover personally signed by Justin!  Click the link above to learn more.  What&rsquo;s more, you can use this special code on the Order Summary page of their website to receive a smashing 25% discount off the price of Immortal War, making the price only &pound;19.14: VAMP-IRAT-ECAP-TAIN.  The offer will last until midnight on the 30th September.&rdquo;<br /><br />The price does not include shipping to Europe, for the United Kingdom (first class) it is &pound;2.12 with up to 14 days for delivery.  Sorry for all those further afield they do not ship that far.<br /><br />For Justin Somper&rsquo;s behind the scenes comments please see <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/behindthescenes/" rel="self">www.vampirates.co.uk</a>.  When <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="self">Vampirates.co.uk</a> say the whole story it does include the world book day book Deed Deep, the actor Daniel Philpott has performed all six of the main VAMPIRATES novels plus DEAD DEEP on audio for W F Howes.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Monday 19th September is International Talk Like A Pirate Day</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Pirates</category><dc:date>2011-09-12T11:59:30+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-464</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/11-september-2011#unique-entry-id-464</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="../pirate/phrases/phrases.html" rel="self" title="Phrases"><img class="imageStyle" alt="jolly roger" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/jollyroger.jpg" width="40" height="39" /></a></div>In a weeks time on Monday 19th September is International Talk Like A Pirate Day (every year).  Please see <a href="http://talklikeapirate.com/about.html" rel="external" title="www.talklikeapirate.com">www.talklikeapirate.com</a>, <a href="http://www.wikihow.com/Talk-Like-a-Pirate" rel="external" title="www.wikihow.com/Talk-Like-a-Pirate">http://www.wikihow.com/Talk-Like-a-Pirate</a> and <a href="http://www.yarr.org.uk/talk/" rel="external" title="www.yarr.org.uk">www.yarr.org.uk/talk</a> for more information.  So time to dust off your pirate outfits and I have listed out some <a href="../pirate/phrases/phrases.html" rel="self" title="Phrases">phrases</a> that might help under our pirates section.  You are welcome to write a post for this blog in pirate talk, just send it via the squeak page.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>International Literacy Day</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2011-09-08T20:40:34+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/04-september-2011#unique-entry-id-462</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/04-september-2011#unique-entry-id-462</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>The Book People and First News wrote today<br />&ldquo;Today is International Literacy Day so I think it's only right we all go home and spend the whole evening reading... bliss!&rdquo;<br />&ldquo;Today is International Literacy Day. What's the last thing you read?&rdquo;<br /><br />I have just lent a book to my neice and mother-in-law, does that count?  The last thing I read was the Hunger Games series (before the film is made).  I am waiting for the latest TimeRiders book to be available at the library and then Power of Six and the latest Skulduggery Pleasant.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>National Bookshop Day</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2011-08-18T22:28:46+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/14-august-2011#unique-entry-id-461</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/14-august-2011#unique-entry-id-461</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>Apparently today is National Bookshop Day in Australia.  I hope everyone enjoyed the last book they read.<br /><br /><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Connor</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Vampirates</category><dc:date>2011-08-10T23:20:07+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-460</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-460</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>Bob Lea wrote &ldquo;I&rsquo;ve been working on the cover for Vampirates Empire Of Night for the Polish publishers (they don't like the new UK covers) they wanted to feature Connor so here he is! This is slightly different from the book cover version, this one's more grainy and I've muted the colours a bit. And he's bigger because I don't have to allow for titles and stuff. And I've put a black vignette around it.&rdquo;<br />Please see <a href="http://boblea.deviantart.com/gallery/369321#/d3hrffx" rel="self">http://boblea.deviantart.com/gallery/369321#/d3hrffx</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stage Tour Schedule</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-08-10T22:47:35+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-459</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-459</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>Tour Schedule 2011<br />For web addresses and phone numbers please see <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a><br /><br />September<br />Sat 17	1pm			LINCOLN - LPAC<br />Sat 24	3pm			BARKING	 - Broadway Theatre		<br />Sun 25	11am, 2pm	BRIGHTON - Brighton Dome, Pavilion Theatre<br /><br />October<br />Sat 8	1pm, 3.30pm	HEMEL HEMPSTEAD - Old Town Hall<br />Wed 12	7pm 			ALDERSHOT - West End Centre<br />Thurs 13	1.30pm, 7pm 	LONDON - Redbridge Drama Centre<br />Sat 15	2.30pm		PETERBOROUGH - Key Theatre<br />Sat 22	2pm			MIDDLESEX - Harrow Arts Centre<br />Mon 24	2pm			DERBY - Guildhall Theatre<br />Tues 25	2.30pm		WELWYN GARDEN CITY - Hawthorne Theatre<br />Wed 26	2.30pm		WELWYN GARDEN CITY - Hawthorne Theatre<br />Thurs 27	8pm			SALISBURY - Salisbury Arts Centre<br />Fri 28	2pm, 7pm		LONDON - Greenwich Theatre<br />Sat 29	1.30, 3.30pm	NORWICH - Norwich Playhouse<br /><br />November &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; <br />Sat 5	3pm			LONDON - Stratford Circus<br />Sat 12	11.30am		FOLKESTONE - Quarterhouse<br />Sun 13	11am, 1.30pm	BRACKNELL - South Hill Park<br />Tues 15	7.30pm		NOTTINGHAM - Lakeside Arts Centre &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;  &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp; <br />Wed 16	1.30, 7.30pm	NOTTINGHAM - Lakeside Arts Centre<br />Sat 19	5pm			CHELTENHAM - Bacon Theatre<br />Fri 25	7pm			CRAWLEY - Hawth Studio<br />Sat 26	3pm, 6pm		LEAMINGTON SPA - Royal Spa Centre<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Twitter Comments</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-08-10T22:38:52+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-458</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-458</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>Courtesy of Twitter, here is what has been happening with Vampirates turning a book into a stage show.<br /><br />Friday 10th June 2011<br />New "VAMPIRATES" family show touring from September 2011 ... based on @justinsomper novels! Watch this space!<br /><br />Thursday 16th June 2011<br />First dates and Autumn 2011 touring schedule for VAMPIRATES now up at - gavinrobertson.com/news.htm<br /><br />Saturday 18th June 2011<br />Live show coming in the Autumn!! It's going to be fun!!<br /><br />Thursday 30th June 2011<br />"Vampirates" script and marketing meet today! Funded by Arts Council England as of last week! :) Moving on...!<br /><br />Saturday 2nd July 2011<br />ACE funding for "Vampirates". So, not all bad news! :)<br /><br />Thursday 7th July 2011<br />And today we have 'Vampirates' casting stuff, script stuff, set stuff, publicity stuff, and start making the show in two weeks...<br /><br />Monday 18th July 2011<br />Begin work on 'Vampirates' script, do a v/o in ghastly London, meet website designer man for chat, then back to the camper. Hey ho!<br /><br />Wednesday 20th July 2011<br />Started script for 'Vampirates'- general relief!<br /><br />Friday 22nd July 2011<br />Costume thoughtfulness for 'Vampirates' and set collection at the weekend. Preparations begin. And the sun's out! Me like!<br /><br />Sunday 24th July 2011<br />Mixed: Set not ready for 'Vampirates' (tradesman letdown) but costumes may be vibrant. Meet the cast Monday & kick of with - a sea shanty!<br /><br />Monday 25th July 2011<br />Day 1 of 'Vampirates' - a sea shanty, good cake, and whisky. A Good Start - official.<br /><br />Tuesday 26th July 2011<br />Fab first five mins of 'Vampirates'- stylish, economical, fluid & well acted. Can i write my own reviews already?! Director Enthusiasm! :)<br /><br />Wednesday 27th July 2011<br />'Vampirates': 14 mins so far! I love creating a new production! :) All hail @danny_bright for fab soundscapes so far ...& deadly accuracy!<br /><br />Thursday 28th July 2011<br />Another day making 'Vampirates' -a storm to adjust, two new characters to introduce, and the arrival (finally) of three BIG treasure chests!<br /><br />Friday 29th July 2011<br />End of week 1 for 'Vampirates' devising: 30 mins of good material - a challenge not to overrun methinks! And.still no set! Grrr!<br /><br />Sunday 31st July 2011<br />30% thru making 'Vampirates'. August = 'happening month'!<br /><br />Monday 1st August 2011<br />'Vampirates': day 1, week 2: Stage choreography, acting with underscore, set doors that won't work. The usual bish bash of devising! :)<br /><br />Tuesday 2nd August 2011<br />A hard but good 'Vampirates' day - show could-if anything- be a bit long! But we'll finish devising it before we make cuts!<br /><br />Wednesday 3rd August 2011<br />We continue devising 'Vampirates'. More choreography today!<br />'Vampirates' getting tiring! Arrr me hearities! Maybe we should be rehearsing in Hastings come 'Pirate Day'..!?<br />I just MAY be within two scenes of the end of the 'Vampirates' script. This is encouraging! :)<br /><br />Thursday 4th August 2011<br />'Vampirates' fans! I think you'll be pleased with our take for the stage show. Amazing what 3 actors can do!! :)<br /><br />Saturday 6th August 2011<br />A weekend doctoring 'Vampirates' set, re-doing publicity, buying costume bits<br /><br />Monday 8th August 2011<br />Meanwhile - dahn sarf it's week 3 of 'Vampirates'- pressure on, but looking good overall! Fab cast and a fab find in composer @danny_bright<br /><br />Tusday 9th August 2011<br />Well theatre folk, we seem to have a new show - 'Vampirates' first dress run tomorrow and looking hopeful! :)<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Stage Version</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-08-09T22:14:07+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-457</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-457</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="3swords" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/3swords.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>&rdquo;I run a touring theatre company Scene Productions and we are delighted to be producing the first ever stage version of VAMPIRATES (Demons of the Ocean) We are working with Justin Somper and it is shaping up to be a fantastic family show. I was wondering if you would be happy to advertise it on your site? We are trying to access the books many fans and this seemed like a great place to start. For tour info please see our website <a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk" rel="self">www.sceneproductions.co.uk</a>&rdquo;<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Quiet</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2011-08-09T22:13:50+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-456</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/07-august-2011#unique-entry-id-456</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="mouse" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/mouse.jpg" width="41" height="41" /></div>I have been a bit quiet as I have been trying to continue using BTFon.  Sadly very little seems to load up with a shaky internet connection.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bording Schools</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2011-07-19T12:38:45+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-455</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-455</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>I wonder how much the Pirate Academy costs a year? as the Economics Society at Lehigh University have worked out that Hogwarts would cost about &pound;26,816 per year.  Please see <a href="http://www.firstnews.co.uk/news/want-to-go-to-hogwarts-with-harry-potter-it-will-cost-you-26816-per-year-i5174" rel="self">http://www.firstnews.co.uk/</a> for the whole article.  It does explain why the Weasley&rsquo;s were so poor, especially as that is more than I have earned as a yearly salary.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Vampirates Blog</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Justin Somper</category><category>Theatre</category><dc:date>2011-07-19T11:00:18+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-454</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-454</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>The Captain has a new blog out after his tours.  He mentions in it more about the Screen Productions adaptation of the Vampirates books (<a href="http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27" rel="self">http://www.sceneproductions.co.uk/tourdetail.asp?id=27</a>) and there is a new fan site Tempest Dhampires (<a href="http://www.tempestdhampires.com/" rel="self">http://www.tempestdhampires.com/</a>).  Please take the opportunity to check them out.<br /><br />To read the whole blog it is as always found on the VIP section of the official Vampirates website <a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/backfromtouringtheuk/default.aspx" rel="self">http://www.vampirates.co.uk/vip-page/blog/backfromtouringtheuk/default.aspx</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Heritage Museums</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Pirates</category><dc:date>2011-07-18T22:07:15+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-453</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/17-july-2011#unique-entry-id-453</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="kegs" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/kegs.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>Now the holidays are here, I thought I would mention the small museums around the place can be quite interesting especially on rainy days.<br /><br />The last one I visited was in Polperro, South Cornwall, England.  Being in Cornwall their heritage museum includes smuggling and fishing.  From contraband goods from Guernsey to the murder of a Customs Officer and even more recent stuff like Customs & Excise and Police seizing a large amounts of smuggled cannabis.<br /><br />Please see <a href="http://www.polperro.org/museum.html" rel="self">http://www.polperro.org/museum.html</a> and <a href="http://www.talland.org/smuggling.html" rel="self">http://www.talland.org/smuggling.html</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>The Tempest</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2011-07-14T12:00:01+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/10-july-2011#unique-entry-id-452</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/10-july-2011#unique-entry-id-452</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="repairs" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/repairs.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>It had to happen sometime, but William Shakespeare did pick the title &ldquo;The Tempest&rdquo; way before the internet arrived and so the tempest twins website.  So here is a shameless plug for my son&rsquo;s school as they are doing the tempest as it links in with the name of the website.  I am off to see it tonight and my son thinks it is &ldquo;good, well better than most school plays&rdquo; and he talked about it without being prompted.  Which if anyone know my boy or a boy at the top of middle school is high praise.<br /><br /><div class="image-right"><img class="imageStyle" alt="kegs" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/kegs-2.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></div>But please support any school near you doing their school plays, as by the comments below you can see how much work both teachers, assistance and students put into school performances.<br /><br />Comments from parents after seeing the performance during the day yesterday were: &ldquo;What a talented year 6 we have! The Tempest was amazing! Well done ... all that blood, sweat & tears most definitely paid off&rdquo; and &ldquo;I took ... to see her big brother in it and it brought her to tears...she really got in to it so just shows how good it was if a Year 1 found it so emotional!  Well done all, cant wait to see it again tomorrow. Good luck tonight.&rdquo;<br /><br />.. and the producer &ldquo;Would like to encourage everyone to come and see the Year 6 Production of The Tempest, either this Thursday or Friday at 7pm. Amazing acting, singing and dancing from our super talented Year 6 children. (Great show even if you don't know the story - it doesn't matter - it's an easy one to pick up.)&rdquo; and &ldquo;Our amazing Yr 6 children are starring in what is being hailed as "one of the best school productions ever" and "way beyond school production standard". With fantastic acting, singing and dancing, a great set and backdrop, some fantastic costumes and a renewed buzz for Shakespeare, it's a show not to be missed!&rdquo;  &rdquo;All proceeds go towards some new and much needed lighting for the junior hall for future productions. xx&rdquo;<br /><br />So if interested tickets are available at the door for the 7pm performance on Thursday 14th July and Friday 15th July at The Coombes Infant School, Arborfield, Reading.<br /><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>St Bede&#x27;s Catholic High School</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Justin Somper</category><dc:date>2011-07-08T16:46:19+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/03-july-2011#unique-entry-id-451</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/03-july-2011#unique-entry-id-451</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>The Captain&rsquo;s Immortal War Schools Tour has got into the news paper.<br />Please see <a href="http://www.blackpoolgazette.co.uk/news/daily-feature/shiver_me_timbers_1_3551947" rel="self">http://www.blackpoolgazette.co.uk/news/daily-feature/shiver_me_timbers_1_3551947</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Under 12 Reading Challenge</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Books</category><dc:date>2011-07-05T12:08:42+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/03-july-2011#unique-entry-id-450</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/03-july-2011#unique-entry-id-450</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="books" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/books.jpg" width="42" height="40" /></div>Our local library has send out a message about the summer reading challenge.  &ldquo;Summer Reading Challenge for 2011 is Circus Stars. Its aimed at children aged 5 to 12 years old. Wokingham Libraries is challenging children to read 6 books over the summer holidays. The challenge starts on Saturday July 16, so pop along to your local library to get started!&rdquo;<br />Please see <a href="http://www.circus-stars.org.uk/" rel="self">http://www.circus-stars.org.uk/</a><br /><br />If you are under 12 years old give it a go, if you are over, I am sure you can help encourage someone under twelve to have a go.  Sharing reading is always fun and so is reading to younger children (provided they like the book).  I know what my daughter is going after, she has recently got into pirate dinosaurs, but is still madly into mermaids.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Updated Address</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Justin Somper</category><dc:date>2011-07-01T16:54:00+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/26-june-2011#unique-entry-id-449</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/26-june-2011#unique-entry-id-449</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><a href="http://www.vampirates.co.uk/" rel="external" title="www.vampirates.co.uk"><img class="imageStyle" alt="vampirates" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/vampirates.jpg" width="40" height="40" /></a></div>For those of you looking to send anything to Justin Somper here is the updated address.  The publishers have apparently moved since the captain gave us his address on his blog November 2009, when he wrote "you can send stuff to me c/o Simon & Schuster Children's Books (Publicity), ....&rdquo;.  The new address is &ldquo;1st Floor, 222 Gray's Inn Road, London WC1X 8HB&rdquo;.<br />]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Skull and Cuff Links</title><dc:creator>mice@mindless.com</dc:creator><category>Side Tracked</category><dc:date>2011-07-01T13:00:44+01:00</dc:date><link>http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/26-june-2011#unique-entry-id-448</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/26-june-2011#unique-entry-id-448</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="image-left"><img class="imageStyle" alt="skullcufflinks.jpg" src="http://www.tempesttwins.co.uk/blog/files/skullcufflinks.jpg" width="63" height="41" /></div>Our ship&rsquo;s entertainer, One Smoking Baritone</a>, (yes the one that looks like Sidorio) has recently become the front man for a covers band.  If you want to check out there facebook page please see <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/Skull-Cuff-Links/169091999822458" rel="self">http://www.facebook.com/pages/Skull-Cuff-Links/169091999822458</a><br />]]></content:encoded></item></channel>
</rss>